<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Naman Balaji</title><link>https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/</link><description>Recent content on Naman Balaji</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 01:24:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GFS</title><link>https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/blogs/gfs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 01:24:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/blogs/gfs/</guid><description>The Google File System (2003) - Paper Summary Why are we reading the GFS paper? Incorporates many of the recurring themes in Distributed Systems: parallel performance, fault tolerance, replication, consistency. Successful real-world design. BigTable, MapReduce built on top of GFS. Well-written systems paper - details from the application to the network. What were the main contributions of the GFS paper to the industry in 2003? Despite writing about basic ideas of distribution, sharding, fault-tolerance, the use of GFS was huge in scale (larger scale than most academic systems).</description></item><item><title>Map Reduce</title><link>https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/blogs/map-reduce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 16:48:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://namanbalaji.github.io/Portfolio-Website/blogs/map-reduce/</guid><description>MapReduce: Simplified Data Processing on Large Clusters MapReduce is a programming model and an associated implementation for processing and generating large data sets. Users specify a map function that processes a key/value pair to generate a set of intermediate key/value pairs, and a reduce function that merges all intermediate values associated with the same intermediate key.
Programs written in this functional style are automatically parallelised and executed on a large cluster of commodity machines.</description></item></channel></rss>